<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emerald Garden</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Emerald Garden</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Diversity of Life</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-01-05-diversity-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-01-05-diversity-of-life/</guid>
      <description>I will argue that every scrap of biological diversity is priceless, to be learned and cherished, and never to be surrendered without a struggle.
 – E.O. Wilson
Leeks. In the ground.
 I have a variety of leek in my home garden that came about through my incompetence as a gardener. Or possibly due to being sleep-deprived from becoming a new father. Either way, it came about by chance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Blank Slate</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-12-20-blank-slate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-12-20-blank-slate/</guid>
      <description>The garden to the rear of Emerald House. The view looks south with the Emerald House to the left and the ploughed garden space surrounding the grape vine to the upper right. Photo courtesy of Onji Scott-Price
 The snow from last weeks storm was still on the ground when the committee met at Emerald House on Saturday. Before the snow had arrived, the the winter rye ground cover crop had germinated and tiny blades could be seen across the plot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marina F. Andrews Garden Site Visit</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-11-21-andrews-site-visit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-11-21-andrews-site-visit/</guid>
      <description>The Committee at the Marina F. Andrews Community Garden, courtesy of Ben Harden
 Another rich fall day and another opportunity for the committee to meet outdoors. This time, we were at the Marina F Andrews Community Garden down Berry Patch Lane at Tony Andrews Farm.
Again, Dick Pooley was our guide. The committee had decided that a good place to start our planning was to learn more about this community garden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Ground</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-11-14-breaking-ground/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-11-14-breaking-ground/</guid>
      <description>Image courtesy of Dick Pooley
 Today we broke ground on the Emerald Community Garden.
It was a warm day. Light sweater weather. One of those fall days where the sun seems to refuse to accept it’s winter role as a supporting character. We assembled on the grass behind Emerald House. Some with a long history with the property and others, like me, coming here for the first time. Some who will act in a supporting role from organizations like Farming Falmouth and the East Falmough Village Association and others looking to form the committee that will bring the garden into existence from this point forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selectboard Approve Lease for Community Garden</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-11-09-land-leased-for-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-11-09-land-leased-for-garden/</guid>
      <description>Image courtesy of Gene M. Marchand, Falmouth Enterprise
 At their meeting on Nov 9th, the Falmouth Selectboard unanimously approved a lease for Farming Falmouth to establish a community garden on the historic Emerald House property at 67 Davisville Road in East Falmouth. The lease is for a 5633 square foot space immediately to the rear of the house, enough space to accommodate 30 gardeners on 10 foot by 10 foot plots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>History</title>
      <link>/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/history/</guid>
      <description>The Emerald family homestead on Davisville Road stands as one reminder of an extraordinary period in Falmouth’s history. The late 1800s introduced an important new element to the community. The Portuguese culture was admirable and the agricultural vision of the new immigrants was remarkable. A century after the first immigration their descendants are vital contributors to the life of the town. Now that the town has bought the Emerald property, we have an opportunity to insure that future generations understand and appreciate this period of history</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Comment</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>  Mailing list Our mailing list will be coming soon…
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Garden</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>The Community Garden will be opening in May 2021 on a 6000 sq ft plot at the Historic Emerald House property on Davisville Road, East Falmouth.
Breaking ground on the community Garden, Nov 2020. Photo courtesy of Dick Pooley
 Area leased to Emerald Community Garden
  This garden will be Falmouth’s second community garden, following on from the success of the Marina F.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>